# Kenneth Kaijage

586 Falcon Ridge Rd Woodbury, MN 55125 ■ kennykaijage@gmail.com ② (763)-742-2834

Portfolio: Kenny Kaijage Portfolio

Linkedln: Ken Kaijage

## SUMMARY

An experienced professional with a Bachelor's degree in Statistics and a minor in Economics with a passion of understanding data. Analytical, action oriented, and hardworking with a strong ability of utilizing critical thinking and teamwork to solve problems.

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Minnesota-Twin Cities** 

**Minneapolis, MN** September 2016 – May 2020

Bachelor of Arts, Major in Statistics, Minor in Economics

- Cumulative GPA: 3.08/4.0; Dean's list Spring 2020.
   Area of Emphasis; Statistical Practice.
- Relevant Coursework: Intro to C++; Theory of Statistics; Regression and Correlated Data; Intermediate Microeconomics; Intermediate Macroeconomics; Introduction to Statistical Computing; Applied Statistics; Public Economics; Statistics Designing Experiments; Communication for Statisticians.

### SKILLS

Languages: SQL, Python, R, C++, HTML

Libraries: Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scipy Stats, Polars, tidyr, Dplyr, ggplot, sqldf, rodbc

Databases: SQL Server, MySQL, PostGres, Snowflake

Tools: VS Code, R Studio, Spyder, Jupyter Notebook, Github, Azure Data Studio, Dbeaver, Tableau, Microsoft Excel, Power Query, Microsoft Power Automate Certifications: Azure Fundamentals, Azure Data Fundamentals, Northwestern 101: Leading with Analytics, Certificate of Competency in SQL, Tableau Desktop Specialist

Other: Teamwork, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving, Data Analytics and Reporting, Database Management, Leadership, Business Process Design, Statistical Analysis

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Optum Eden Prairie, MN

Healthcare Economics Consultant

September 2024 - Present

- Enabled a 25% increase in reporting efficiency by optimizing database queries and streamlining data ingestion processes through the design of scalable
   Snowflake database architecture such as utilizing stored procedures to support real-time data integration from the Midwest and Mid-Atlantic care delivery organizations.
- Improving cross-departmental collaboration by facilitating monthly analytics presentations and resulting in the rollout of a \$1M cost-reduction initiative.

  Senior Healthcare Economics Analyst

  January 2024 September 2024
  - Developed and optimized the Snowflake database infrastructure to integrate data from care delivery organizations which reduced the reporting time by 30% and enabled actionable insights into resource utilization, treatment effectiveness and patient coverage.
  - Developed Tableau dashboards to that identified \$2M in potential cost savings by highlighting areas of opportunity across Midwest and Mid-Atlantic care delivery networks.
  - Partnered with data engineers across different teams to design and maintain automated data pipelines, ensuring 99.9% data integrity and consistency across multiple sources of truth, while improving the accuracy and efficiency of enterprise-wide reporting.

Accenture Minneapolis, MI

Senior Analyst Consulting Development Analyst November 2022 – January 2024 August 2021 – November 2022

Project Experiences

Data Scientist

August 2023 – January 2023

- Ingested over 1200 survey responses using Python and provided key insights on employee feedback to senior leadership.
- Applied statistical techniques such as standard deviation, bell curve and correlation to assess employee feedback and recommended a 2-4% average score increase for 2024 based on five-year trends.
- Processed and cleaned raw funding data using Python and developed an Excel dashboard to visualize funding distribution across offices and recipients over the past five years.

Data Quality Analyst

July 2022 – July 2023

- Developed SQL Queries for weekly refreshable Excel reports and automated follow-up emails to client project managers and enhanced data quality and integrity.
- Developed SQL Queries and data validations and utilized Excel tools such as Pivot Tables to generate reports and metrics that enabled stakeholders to understand business performance.
- Developed a Tableau dashboard for data cleaning in March 2023 that monitored 26 teams for data governance compliance, improve deployment timelines, cost savings, and budget optimization.
- Developed Excel reports using SQL to conduct monthly audits for data cleaning of 100+ projects which helped the client to maximize capitalization and save over \$50 million in costs.

Business Analyst January 2022 – June 2022

- Analyzed visit types using Excel to identify top patient visit reasons per center from 2019 to 2022 and created Excel visuals that prioritized five high-volume centers for CRM scheduling.
- Analyzed block usage data in Excel to determine peak scheduling blocks and created visuals and reports that led to the recommendation to remove underused blocks from 2021 and onwards.
- Supported clinical scripting workflow through scripting and analyzed keyword mapping in Excel to ensure accurate symptom matching within the CRM scheduling framework.

Data Analyst September 2021 – December 2021

- Developed and automated data processes to integrate multiple sources that supported reporting and dashboard creation.
- Constructed data tables and views in Microsoft SQL Server for ETL and SSI package development to facilitate data migration.
- Created design documents, data tables and structures in the ETL development process and created test scripts that facilitated the data cleaning and data organization from ETL to the data migration.
- Loaded the data into the server for clean-up, end-to-end testing and migration to support dashboard building, reporting, and wireframe completion.

US Bank
Global Securities Specialist
June 2020 – August 2021

- Collaborated with clients and administrators to establish and oversee global trade accounts.
- Analyzed and corrected erroneous trade instructions in the market using SWIFT and inbound trade communications.
- Provided recommendations to global teams to align with client and business requirements.
- Contributed to internal projects at team-specific and global custody levels.